Yes, yes,
ừ ừ
hello everyone. I am Vu
gì xin chào quý vị và các bạn Tôi là Vũ
Hoang Huy, a member of the information
Hoàng Huy thành viên trong ban thông tin
committee of the Golden Club practicing the Six Harmonies.
câu lạc bộ cục vàng tập tu Lục Hòa hôm
Today is the 7th day of the Lunar New Year, the year of the Rooster. People from all
nay là ngày mùng 7 tết năm Đinh Dậu nhân
directions are still flocking to
dân Thập Phương vẫn đang nô nước về chùa
Ba Vang Pagoda to worship Buddha. It's a very large
Ba Vàng lễ Phật rất là đông như một
tradition of the
truyền thống không thể thiếu của dân tộc
Vietnamese people. Everyone prepares flowers and fruits to bring to the
Việt Nam vào nhà đều sắm sửa hoa trái về
pagoda to offer and worship Buddha during the New
chùa cúng giường và lễ Phật vào dịp tết
Year. It is this auspicious connection stemming from
đến xuân về do chính cái Duyên khởi từ
this place of reverence and filial piety that
nơi cũng tâm cung kính hiếu đạo này mà
increases blessings for each family.
mỗi gia đình đều được tăng trưởng phúc
In Buddhism, there is a saying: "Reciting Buddha's name
lành trong đạo Phật có câu niệm phật một
once brings immeasurable blessings; worshiping Buddha once eradicates countless sins."
câu Phước Sanh vô lượng lễ phật một lễ
Coming to the pagoda to worship Buddha
tội diệt hà sa về đến chùa lễ phật chứa
holds many sacred meanings, and to
đựng rất nhiều ý nghĩa linh thiêng và để
help visitors come to worship
trợ giúp cho khách thập phương về lễ
Buddha in an orderly and solemn manner, the
phật được nền nếp và trang nghiêm
temple's ritual committee has made a significant contribution. We would like to
hạ lễ ở chùa sau đây Chúng tôi xin được
speak with a Buddhist from the
trò chuyện với một phật tử trong ban Hà
ritual committee, representing all the Buddhists.
Lễ đại diện cho toàn thể các phật tử nó
Speaking of their feelings, they are
lên tâm tư tình cảm của mình thì được
doing volunteer work at Ba Vang Pagoda. A woman
làm công quả dân chùa Ba Vàng
passed by, "Excuse me, could you tell me the name of the thug?" "
ô tô qua cô cho con hỏi tên côn đồ gì
I'll give you my name," she said.  I'm a member of the
được không ạ tôi cho cháu cô tên là
offering committee at
nguyệt ở ban hạ lễ thuộc Ban Hưng đăng
Ba Vang Pagoda.
của chùa Ba Vàng
I'd like to ask you about the daily work of your offering committee.
con xin hỏi cô là công việc của ban hạ
As I've seen, because of the
thế nào đó không ạ Như cháu đã thấy vì
large number of people and offerings, you
lượng người nên lễ vật quá đông nên cô
and the Buddhist followers in the committee assist. After
và các phật tử trong ban trợ giúp khi
people bring flowers, fruits, and other offerings to the Buddha,
mọi người đem hoa quả vật thật cúng Phật
you bring the offerings inside for
xong thì các cô mang lễ vào trong này để
safekeeping. Then, when they
bảo quản giúp Sau đó họ đi lễ phật rồi
return after praying, you return the chocolates and other items to the pilgrims.
quay lại các cô sẽ gửi lại cho chính chủ
With the
sô-cô-la với một đồ khách hành hương
increasing number of pilgrims,
ngày càng gia tăng như vậy thì cô và các
what solutions do you and the Buddhist followers have to ensure that
phật tử có những giải pháp nào để cho
the offerings and rituals are conducted in a
việc cúng và lễ thuật được diễn ra một
solemn and orderly manner?
cách trang nghiêm và nề nếp 10
Right at the entrance, pilgrims are
ngay ở lối vào khách hành hương sẽ được
guided to the area where they arrange their offerings and bring them to the
hướng dẫn đến khu vực xếp lễ rồi đem nên
Three Jewels. Each offering is only
cúng dường tam bảo ở mỗi lễ chỉ được
conducted for 10 minutes to avoid
tiến hành trong 10 phút để tránh tình
congestion and maintain solemnity. The
trạng ùn tắc gây mất trang nghiêm các
Buddhist followers in the committee always assist
phật tử trong ban hành lễ luôn trợ giúp
visitors throughout the process. Do you
khách trong suốt quá trình lễ phật
feel happy and joyful working like this? Are there any other
các cô làm việc như thế thì thấy thân
difficulties you encounter?
gặp những khó khăn gì không ạ Các cơ và
The ceremony was very
các phật tử trong ban hành lễ đều rất
joyful and cheerful because for all
vui vẻ và hoan hỷ bởi vì đối với mọi
the people who came to the temple, their sincere
người dân khi đến chùa họ có lòng thành
offering of flowers and fruits to the Buddhas
dâng hoa quả cúng dường Chư Phật là đã
showed their reverence for the Three Jewels.
thể hiện tâm cung kính đối với tam bảo
However, due to some old beliefs, some
tuy nhiên do một số quan niệm cũ mà họ
still held the thought of offering first and then enjoying the offerings themselves.
vẫn còn tư tưởng trước cúng sau hưởng
Therefore, the nuns and Buddhist followers in the
độc nên các cô và các phật tử trong ban
ceremony committee still assisted them in the complete ritual,
hạ lễ vẫn trợ giúp cho họ phần lễ bái
praying that from
được chu viên để nguyện cầu cho họ từ
this respectful heart, they would be born into a joyful heart
nơi tâm cung kính này sinh ra Tâm hoan
for all eternity, and that wherever they were born, they
hỷ Đời Đời Kiếp Kiếp sinh ra nơi nào
would encounter the true Dharma of the Buddha to
cũng được gặp chính pháp của Phật để tu
practice. Regarding the difficulties of the committee,
em về khó khăn của banco thì trong năm
last year, 2016, the year of the
nay thì năm ngoái là năm 2016 là năm tết
Monkey, the nuns encountered some
Bính Thân chị các cô có gặp một số khó
difficulties such as the large number of visitors and
khăn như lượng khách đến lễ vặn quá đông
some visitors refusing to accept less than
một số khách không chịu nhận thiếu nên
their offerings. When they returned after making their offerings, they didn't recognize their trays. This year, the
ra mâm lễ của họ trong năm nay thì ban
committee helped by suggesting that
cô đã giúp kinh nghiệm là Đề nghị các
visitors happily accept the vouchers, and
khách đến lễ phật hoan hỷ nhận phiếu và
at this point, the committee has not
đến tại thời điểm này thì ban cô chưa
encountered any difficulties. Thank you, my dear. I
gặp khó khăn gì Cảm ơn cháu nó xin cảm
also wish you, from this place of encouragement, continued growth and
cô cháu cũng chúc cô từ nơi Khuyến tấn
prosperity.  With a kind and benevolent heart, one
người tăng trưởng được tâm thiện lành và
can repay the source of greed, anger,
sẽ trả được nguồn tâm tham chất sân giận
and hatred by cultivating a respectful and virtuous mind.
tăng trưởng tâm cung kính và tân hoa thì
We can see that the disciples who come to
chúng ta có thể thấy những phần Tử lên
Ba Vang Pagoda are like crows, yet in reality, they are like
chùa Ba Vàng Công quạ như được chưa Thật
tigers, so their minds and bodies are always
ra hổ nên thân tâm của họ lúc nào cũng
joyful and full of vitality—truly
hoan hỷ tràn đầy sức sống thật là kỳ
miraculous. We also hope that everyone who comes to the
diệu chúng tôi cũng mong ai ai về đến
pagoda will learn
chùa cũng đều học được tâm cung kính Tầm
this respectful and joyful mind, so that the country may have
Hoan Hỷ này khiến cho đất nước được hòa
peace, the people may be happy, and the world may have no more
bình nhân dân an lạc thế giới không còn
wars. We also pray that
chiến tranh đồng thời cũng nguyện cho
everyone may be freed from impure thoughts, always
mọi người thoát khỏi tâm cầu uế luôn
living with a peaceful and diligent mind,
luôn sống với tâm an lạc tinh tấn thực
practicing the Buddha's teachings, and achieving
hành Giáo Pháp của đức Phật mà thành tựu
the source of loving-kindness, compassion, joy, and equanimity, bringing
các nguồn tâm từ bi hỷ xả đem lại hạnh
happiness to themselves and others.
phúc cho mình và cho mọi người I